Resume

Bio: I am currently interested in cartography, as well as youth experiences within public k-12 schools. These two interests converge when dealing with access to quality education and teachers. Additionally, I am interested in the history

Education University of Wisconsin, Madison

Doctor of Philosophy in Education Policy Studies Anticipated Graduation Date: May 2019

Northern Illinois University

Master of the Arts in History Graduation Date: May 2011

University of Tennessee at Chattanooga

Master of Education in Secondary Education

Graduation Date: May 2009

University of Tennessee at Chattanooga

Bachelor of the Arts in History

Cum Laude

Graduation Date: December 2007

Honors *Phi Alpha Theta* History Honor Society

Relevant Experience

University of Wisconsin, Madison

June 2015- Current

Department of Curriculum and Instruction *Instructor*

- Teach a curriculum that focuses on second language acquisition theory.
- Assist new teachers develop appropriate scaffolding techniques for ELLs

Madison Metropolitan School District

June 2015- July 2015

Madison, WI

Enrichment Teacher

- Create lesson plans that supplement the core content instruction.
- Teach sportsmanship through athletics.
- Promote literacy through library instruction.

University of Wisconsin, Madison

September 2013-June 2015

Department of Curriculum and Instruction

ESL Infusion Instructor (Part Time)

- Develop and administer ESL instruction workshops for pre-service teachers.
- Assist pre-service teachers with integrating language goals for ELLs.
- Promote the significance of culturally relevant teaching

Boulder Valley School District, CO

June 2014- July 2014

Boulder, CO

Summer School Teacher, 4th Grade

- Develop a scaffold curriculum for science literacy education.
- Provide culturally and linguistically responsive education.

Putnam County Schools, TN

September 2012- May 2013

Algood, TN

21st Century/LEAPS Extended Learning Instructor (Part Time)

- Teach Latin American & World Cultures, and Chess as after-school enrichment courses to students in grades 5-8.
- Teach Greek Mythology and Creative Writing as after-school enrichment courses to third and fourth grade students.
- Provide homework assistance to students enrolled in the extended learning program.

Putnam County Schools, TN

August 2011-May 2013

Algood Elementary, Algood Middle, and Northeast Elementary Schools Cookeville, TN

English Language Learners Teacher (Full Time)

- Develop and deliver lesson plans with the objective of improving ELL students' English oral, reading, and writing skills.
- Collaborate with content teachers to tailor the delivery of content to match the students' ability level.
- Provide inclusion services for students.

Northern Illinois University

August 2010-May 2011

DeKalb, IL

Teaching Assistant: Art History (Part Time)

• Teach three discussion sections (roughly twenty students each), which augment the lecture portion of the Introduction to the Visual Arts.

- Administer bi-weekly exams; grade student essays and in-class writing assignments.
- Act as an academic liaison between the students and the Art History professors.

Camp Buckskin

June 2010-August 2010

Minneapolis, MN
Reading Teacher (Full Time)

- Tailor individualized reading and writing programs for students with learning disabilities in correspondence with IEPs.
- Provide a comprehensive report of each student's progress and effective teaching strategies utilized during the summer, which may be applied to upcoming academic year.
- Assist camp counselors during evening and weekend camp programs and activities.

Affiliations Book Selection Committee at Algood Middle School August 2012-May 2013

Papers Presented

Dare the schools work alone: Work toward social Justice? (Re)Imagining Community based spaces as sites for critical education

• Roundtable Discussion presented at American Education Research Association Chicago, IL (April 18, 2015)

ELLs and the Power of Naming.

• Presented at the National Multicultural Educational Association in Tuscon, Arizona (November 9, 2014)

Educational Furniture and Classroom Arrangement in American Progressive Education

• Presented at: The Third Annual History Graduate Student Conference at Northern Illinois University (October 22, 2010)

William Jennings Bryan: The 1896 bid for Presidency

• Presented at: History Between the Hedges II Conference at University of Georgia (April 5, 2008)

Fact and Fiction in the Writing of Roman History

• Presented at: Southeastern Student History Conference at University of Tennessee at Chattanooga (February 15, 2007)